ALOK BARSODE

Mobile: +447568323039 website: alokbarsode.uk email: barsodealok@gmail.com

I am a London based UX/front-end developer with over 10 years of diverse development experience. I am passionate about technology, open source and building exciting products. I have worked extensively on Linux and open source projects. I am currently exploring opportunities with emerging standards like web components and new front-end frameworks like Angular. I have worked with agile methodology (scrum) and have acted as a scrum master on projects. I am self-motivated, open-minded and have an out-of-the-box thinking attitude.

EXPERIENCE

Modern Web Stack: W3C validated HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and jQuery.

Web frameworks: Angularjs, Nodejs, Web Components (Polymer), Cordova, Express, Bootstrap.

Test frameworks: Jasmine, Protractor and Karma.

Workflow: Responsive Design, Mobile development, SPA.

Dev. tools: Git, npm, bower, grunt, gulp, JIRA, bash shell.

EMPLOYMENT

Intel Inc. (May 2011-July 2015)

Smart Home Hybrid application (LEAD DEVELOPER, ARCHITECT)

Developed a hybrid web application to demonstrate the user experience of Intel's smart home gateways. The application presented different home configurations to the user. The user could then control elements like light bulbs, thermostats, blinds etc. individually or by type. The backend monitored and recorded the patterns of the user and automatically triggered events based on them. Built using web components (Polymer), Cordova/crosswalk and CCA, the application was deployed on nexus devices and laptops for a demo at the Computex trade show in Taiwan. The application was well received at the show and received a recognition award for the efforts.

Classroom Concept Application (Architect, Lead Developer, Scrum Master)

Developed a HTML5 concept application for chrome books, which helped education professionals to create and share content with others. The application also had a sophisticated planning functionality for tutors to plan their courses and share their calendars with other tutors. The application was designed with material design and built with Polymer, CCA and was deployed using the chrome web store.

Content Research Tool for Google Docs (SCRUM MASTER, CODE REVIEWER)

Designed and developed a content research tool for Google Docs. The tool parsed content from a live Google doc document, analysed it using an NLP library, extracting keywords. These keywords were fed to multiple web workers, which worked simultaneously to search for relevant content online (images, articles, quotes etc.). The results were aggregated and presented to the user using a side panel. The user can then drag-and-drop any relevant content in their document. Used web components, web workers and CCA to build this application. It was deployed using Chrome web store. A patent was filed for the unique approach.

Telemetry front-end (LEAD DEVELOPER)

Delivered an android-based UI for telemetry settings for an Intel product. The UI was responsible for user consent to Intel collecting telemetry data from the product, which helped engineers to debug issues and correct problems with OTA updates. The other part of the UI was in the core settings, which exposed telemetry functionality to the user. Build using the android SDK for KitKat and higher versions.

Agile/JIRA workshop for Designers/Developers (PRESENTER)

Conducted a workshop for developers and designers on how to use JIRA for agile development. The workshop was a hands-on fun experience for both developers and designers. Was rewarded for the unique effort and was consulted on various JIRA related issues.

Tizen Networking UI (LEAD DEVELOPER)

Developed and delivered a Gnome based UI for Tizen's networking stack – ConnMan for wireless, oFono for data and BlueZ for tethering. Also contributed to filing bugs and feature enhancements with the individual stacks. Collaborated with designers to deliver a seamless experience to the user.

ConnMan (DEVELOPER)

Developed various features for the open-source networking stack. ConnMan is developed and maintained by Intel as an alternative to other open source networking stacks. It has an impressive architecture and useful features like small footprint, customizable plugins and built-in support for modern technologies like IPv6.

Motorola Mobility. (April 2006-November 2010)

Networking Stack (lead developer, scum master, architect)

Maintained the networking stack for the Linux mobile distribution. Also contributed to ConnMan and BlueZ, the open source projects for networking and Bluetooth respectively.

Codito Technologies. (May 2005-April 2006)

Device Drivers (DEVELOPER)

Developed Real-Time Linux network device drivers.

AWARDS

Intel Recognition award 2015 – Awarded for successfully delivering the smart home application for Computex trade show.

Intel Patent Award 2015 - Awarded for filing a software patent for the unique approach in Content Research Tool. Intel Recognition award 2014 - Awarded for the Agile/JIRA workshop conducted for developers/designers. Intel Recognition award 2014 - Awarded for successfully delivering the Tizen networking UI.

EDUCATION

$Bachelor\ of\ Engineering\ ({\tt COMPUTER\ SCIENCE})$

University of Pune-Pune Institute of Computer Technology, India May 2005